# Sean New

Baltimore, MD 21228 | snew430@gmail.com | (410) 215-6229

Portfolio: <a href="https://seanpnew.com">https://seanpnew.com</a> Github: <a href="https://github.com/snew430">https://github.com/snew430</a>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/snew430/

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer by title, problem solver by heart. I love to take on the challenges that technology gives us whether that's creating a full-stack web application or solving an algorithm problem on LeetCode. Most of my professional career has been in managing people to achieve a common goal which can translate across all fields of work. Living life to the fullest, always self improving, and helping the people around you is my motivation and driving force.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML · CSS · JavaScript · jQuery · MySQL · MongoDB · Express.js · React.js · Node.js

Bootstrap · Handlebars · GitHub · Heroku · Responsive Design · Local Storage · User Authentication

Sass · Object Oriented Programming · APIs · GraphQL · Object Relational Mapping · MVC · PWA's · Jest Testing

#### **PROJECTS**

What's My Tee Time? |https://github.com/snew430/golfbuddy | https://whatsmyteetime.herokuapp.com/

• A MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) golf tournament website designed for private use. Our clients have a fully functioning website to organize each tournament they host twice a year.

WatchSocial | https://github.com/snew430/watchsocial | https://watchsocial.herokuapp.com/

MySQL database application using Node.js, HTML, CSS/Bootstrap, JavaScript, Handlebars, and Express.
 Implements CRUD routes to handle database changes while incorporating Sequelize

Shop-Shop | https://github.com/snew430/shop-shop | https://sean-shop.herokuapp.com/

• A MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js) application using global state context to keep track of an e-commerce site. Avoid prop-drilling in your react app with these concepts.)

## **EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Coding Tutor | 2U - 05/2022 - Present

1-on-1 and group tutoring sessions to help students of 2u/Trilogy Education students learn Full Stack Web Development and Computer Science Skills.

Full Stack Coding Grader/Teaching Assistant | 2U - 05/2022 - Present

Teaching Assistant for a Full Stack Web Development cohort designed to teach students of 2u/Trilogy Education from the basics of HTML to the full MERN stack of web development

Freelancer | Sean New - 05/2022 - Present

Designing and deploying websites for clients using knowledge in Full Stack Web Development

**General Manager** | Dillard's - 05/2014 - 05/2022

Provide direction and planning to oversee the day-to-day operations of a multi-million dollar store in all aspects. Lead a team of managers and associates consisting of 100+ people, recruit top talent prospects, and coordinate successful events to achieve sales plans.

## **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development | Vanderbilt University

Bachelor's Degree | Sport & Exercise Psychology | West Virginia University